A Guide to the August E. Kehr Papers 1949-2000
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
August E. Kehr Papers 1949-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10553-am
ca. 700 items (5 Hollinger boxes)
This collection consists of the papers, 1949-2000, of geneticist, professor, and horticulturist August E. Kehr.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library by August E. Kehr, Hendersonville, North Carolina, on July 31, 2000.
Biographical/Historical Information
August Ernest Kehr (1914- ), geneticist, professor, and horticulturist with the U.S. Department of Agriculture, is a member of the American Rhododendron Society and The Magnolia Society.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of August E. Kehr consist of correspondence with nurserymen and other rhododendron growers in the United States and around the world. Correspondents include Os Blumhardt, Brett and Dorothy Callaway, John D. Carlson, Karl E. Flinck, Maurice and Rosemary Foster, Frank B. Galyon, Mark Haimes, Harry Heinemann, Joseph Hickman, Harold Hopkins, Olav Kalleberg, Mark Krautmann, Wade Mahlke, Frederick G. Meyer, William Moyles, Jay W. Murray, Sonja Nelson, Terry Pennington, the Rhodendron Species Foundation, George Ring, Sir Peter Smithers, and Bob Tomayer. There are also letters from Kehr's wife, Mary Lou Kehr, while he was in Cairo, Egypt, on a project with the United States Department of Agriculture.
Also present are certificates and awards; printed material; articles by other authors, including Stephen L. Krebs and Dan E. Mayers; a small notebook; photographs; programs; information regarding ARS Research Grants; early employment records for Kehr; and his Presidential Address at the Annual Meeting of the ARS in 1977.There is also a cassette tape recording of "Nick Fortescue on the Red Maximum" (March 17, 1991).
Arrangement
Most of the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent. Correspondence pertaining to the American Rhododendron Society and its members has been filed under that name.
Contents List
- Articles (Box 1)
  - "A Cytogenetic Study of Sterile Rhododendron Hybrids" by Stephen L. Krebs n.d.
  - "Genetic Control of Isozyme Variability Among Hybrid Rhdodendrons" by Stephen L. Krebs n.d.
  - "Rhododendrons in the British Isles--An Irreverent Approach" by Dan E. Mayers n.d.
  - "Seeds for our Future: The U.S. National Plant Germplasm System" 1990
  - "The Use of Multilocus Enzyme Markers for Identifying Rhododendron Cultivars" by Stephen L. Krebs n.d.
- Certificates & Awards ca. 1949-1998 (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1960-2000 (Box 1-5)
  - Correspondence: A 1985-1998 (Box 1)
  - American Rhododendron Society 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - American Rhododendron Society--Jay W. Murray, Registrar Plant Names 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - American Rhododendron Society--Sonja Nelson, Journal Editor 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - American Rhododendron Society Research Committee 1984-1996 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: B 1984-1999 (Box 1)
  - Os Blumhardt 1983-1999 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: C 1985-2000 (Box 1)
  - Brett & Dorothy Callaway, Sweetbay Farm 1995-1998 (Box 1)
  - John D. Carlson 1995-2000 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: D 1961-1999 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: E 1985-1998 (Box 2)
  - Employment 1960-1977 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: F 1995-1999 (Box 2)
  - Karl E. Flinck 1985-1998 (Box 2)
  - Maurice and Rosemary Foster 1995-1998 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: G 1978-1999 (Box 2)
  - Frank B. Galyon 1987-1999 (Box 2)
  - Genealogy 1990-1999 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: H 1985-2000, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Mark Haimes 1997-2000 (Box 3)
  - Harry Heinemann 1996-1998 (Box 3)
  - Joseph W. Hickman & Hickman Nursery 1985-2000 (Box 3)
  - Harold Hopkins 1984-1998 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: I-J 1987-2000 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: K 1996-1999 (Box 3)
  - Olav Kalleberg 1993-1999 (Box 3)
  - Mark Krautmann, Heritage Seedlings, Inc. 1995-1999 (Box 3)
  - Mary Lou Kehr, while August Kehr was in Cairo, Egypt, and including a lew letters from Edith Fifer at the U.S.D.A. 1975 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: L 1979-2000 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: M 1989-2000 (Box 3)
  - Magnolia Round Robins 1995-1998 (Box 4)
  - The Magnolia Society, Inc. 1994-2000 (Box 4)
  - Wade Mahlke 1995-2000 (Box 4)
  - Frederick G. Meyer 1995-1999 (Box 4)
  - William Moyles 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: N 1993-1999 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: P 1986-1999 (Box 4)
  - Terry Pennington 1997-1999 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: R 1985-1999 (Box 4)
  - The Rhododendron Species Foundation 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - George Ring 1995-1998 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Sa-Sm 1985-1999 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: So-Sz 1965-1999 (Box 5)
  - Sir Peter Smithers 1996-1998 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: T 1986-1999 (Box 5)
  - Bob Tomayer, Wavecrest Nursery & Landscaping Co. 1996-1999 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: U-V 1985-1999 (Box 5)
  - Unidentified 1967-1998 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: W 1994-1999 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: X-Y-Z 1993-1999 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous 1953-1999 (Box 5)
- Notebook ca. 1987 (Box 5)
- Presidential Address at the Annual Meeting of the American Rhododendron Society, Eugene, Oregon by August Kehr 1977 May (Box 5)
- Research Grants Awarded by the Research Foundation of the American Rhododendron Society 1986-1987 (Box 5)
- U.S.D.A. Award for Superior Service to Dr. August E. Kehr 1975